Guide to the Robert W. Simpson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert W. Simpson papers
1839-1862
1858-1862
MS 1103
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Personal and business correspondence of Robert W. Simpson, ship's log, and business and financial papers concerning the voyages of the Carlyle before and during the Civil War.
Simpson, Robert W.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles Blitzer, 1980.
Biographical / Historical
Robert W. Simpson was from Brunswick, Maine. Between 1858 and 1862 he was captain and part owner of the ship Carlyle, which called at New Orleans, Liverpool, Kronstadt, and possibly other places.
Scope and Contents
Personal and business correspondence of Robert W. Simpson, ship's log, and business and financial papers concerning the voyages of the Carlyle before and during the Civil War.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Business; Shipping; New England; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Economic aspects; Shipmasters; Simpson, Robert W.; Carlyle (Ship)
- Inventory
  - Letters to Robert W. Simpson
    - From brothers and sisters in Brunswick, Maine, and elsewhere in the northeastern United States, 1860 July-1862 March (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
    - From commercial associates in American and foreign ports, especially Taylor, Tipper & Co., ship merchants and brokers of Liverpool, 1860 July-1862 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notebook
    - Record of wages received by Robert W. Simpson, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Log of round-trip voyage between the eastern United States and southeast Asia with instructions for navigating Cape Horn, [1839?]-1841 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Account book for provisions, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Shipping papers, 1847, 1858-1860 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chart of nautical signals, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)